Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Earth Federation has decided to launch
its attack on the special mining base...
...protected by M'Quve's forces.
It is the start of Operation Odessa.
General Revil has sent
all of his forces against M'Quve.
Although the White Base has
returned to the front lines...
...it was at the cost of many lives
including Lt. Matilda.
The Battle of Odessa
Please make the bare minimum of repairs!
The operation has already started!
Just have it ready so I can get going!
I know, I know! Don't yell!
Give him a break. He's a bit edgy
after the loss of Lieutenant Matilda.
Well, the same goes for me too!
Ms. Matilda...
Amuro!
Uh... yes?
You mustn't be preoccupied, Amuro.
We've been ordered to launch. Let's go.
Yeah.
Are you okay?
We're scouting the White Base's route...
...while also getting me used to this thing.
You'll help me, won't you?
Roger that.
The G-Armor's taking off!
Step back now, Fraw Bow!
Amuro. I'm going to use these Gundam
power-up parts that Ms. Matilda brought us.
I need to do some practice runs.
Go ahead, Ms. Sayla.
Please do that.
I'm sorry, Mr. Bright.
Try to be more careful.
Yes, sir.
You don't have to do anything.
Just let me know if you get an SOS.
Yes. I understand, sir.
Fried Chicken, deployment complete!
The Air Forces are running slow.
Someone do something about that!
We need them to send another Dobday!
Borscht team from M'Quve's forces,
you're too far out in front!
Oh, Spirit of Mash...
May you soar into space...
...and drift in eternal happiness.
I'm well aware these soldiers
were recommended by Lady Kycilia.
But how long are they going to waste
time and energy like this?!
Gaia. Ortega. The operation has begun!
We know that already!
We'll have our revenge, no need to nag us.
This is not a revenge mission!
Take out the Trojan Horse that's threatening
us from behind. That's the plan!
Yes, we know!
Ortega! We're heading out.
We'll be approaching
the enemy soon, Ms. Sayla.
Be careful.
Roger! Let me try the touch-and-go
one more time!
We're receiving a message through
code modulation circuit, alpha-gain.
It's General Revil.
What? From General Revil?!
"At 0630 hours, the White Base is to
attack M'Quve's base from the rear."
Contact the G-Armor, Fraw Bow,
and tell them to return to the White Base...
...using cross cycle W.F.
Yes... sir. W.F?
Mm-hm.
Can you really do it properly?
Of course I can. You just keep quiet now.
The enemy's front line is this close?
Did they notice us?
Please lower our altitude now, Ms. Sayla!
They may have spotted us.
Roger!
Looks like a propeller-driven plane.
I'm not that certain...
...but I don't think it's one of Zeon's planes.
I'll check.
I've got it...
A Dragonfly?
A small ferry plane used by the Federation.
Why did it just come out of a Zeon base?
And how come it wasn't shot down?
That's strange.
There's a message from the White Base...
"Return to ship immediately."
What should we do, Amuro?
Aren't you curious, Ms. Sayla?
Yes... Shall we check it out?
Yes!
Come to think of it, Ms. Matilda did say...
...that Zeon seemed to know
every move her Medea would make.
A spy? It's possible.
That's true.
But if the Medeas were shot down
because of a spy...
...we need to reveal the truth
before we begin the operation.
Mr. Bright! Enemy machines approaching
from one o'clock, sir!
What did you say?!
Headed straight for us?!
Yes. But they couldn't have
detected us at this altitude.
There's our proof that we have a spy.
Prepare for anti-air combat.
Guntank, Guncannon, prepare to sortie!
Hey, hold on a moment!
Isn't this ahead of the operation's schedule?
The enemy isn't going to wait
until it's convenient for us!
Don't waste your ammo.
Yeah, okay.
Look, Amuro. The Dragonfly has landed
on the Federation's Big Tray.
Ms. Sayla! Wait for me here.
Identify yourself! Name and assignment!
Gundam of the White Base!
My name is Amuro Ray!
Gundam? This thing?
More importantly, I need you to tell me
where I can find the pilot...
...of the Dragonfly that just landed!
You mean Judock's ferry plane?
He's ordered you to betray your own forces
as soon as the operation begins.
M'Quve is a rather restless man, isn't he.
Since M'Quve knows you won't be attacking...
...he has also ordered his main forces
to focus on General Revil.
I understand.
What is it?
Sir! We've caught a suspicious person.
Suspicious...?
What do you want?
Can we talk alone?
Yes, as you wish.
You may all leave the room.
Sir!
Judock.
Depending on what's discussed in that room,
we might need to interrogate you.
This picture was taken by an official
military data-processing camera...
...and can be used as evidence.
I see...
Are you trying to tell me that
we have a spy aboard the Big Tray?
Yes. If we enlarge the negative,
we should be able to verify the pilot.
You're suggesting that Judock is this spy?
I am.
Then it's capital punishment.
For Judock...
...and for you, as well.
This is a battlefield.
Nobody will ask questions
if a single person is killed. And besides...
I'm a general.
Nobody will listen to a child like you.
I... I thought it was impossible,
but... It's you...
You...
Because of people like you...!
I wish I could say I'd spare your life
in exchange for the negative...
But I don't think so.
Amuro... Great work.
We have this whole conversation on video.
It's more than enough evidence.
No problem.
Please stand up!
You will remain in the brig
until the operation is complete.
You want to say you had your reasons.
But... you're wrong!
Because of people like you...
...dozens of people
have died for nothing!
Do you even realize that?!
Because of people like you...!
Son...
Let's leave the rest for the court martial.
Yes, sir.
The White Base seems to
be engaged in battle.
I suggest you return at once.
Yes sir!
Good luck!
Our forces will begin the attack
from M'Quve's flank!
Big Tray, maximum speed!
G-Armor, prepare for takeoff!
Amuro. We're taking off. Ready?
Roger!
Go!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
The battle of Odessa has begun.
Both M'Quve's and Revil's forces...
...are headed straight for each other,
deploying their maximum resources.
And the White Base is no exception.
He's fast!
Hayato! The Guntank won't stand a chance
against these guys!
Retreat, retreat!
Why you...!
Hands off this one, Dopps!
Just focus on downing the Trojan Horse!
Hurry up and bring in the Guntank!
Keep the mobile suits away!
Amuro! I hope you'll be back real soon!
G-Armor is returning,
from one o'clock, sir!
Good! Prepare to launch the beam rifle!
Amuro! I can see you!
How's the battle going?
Huh?
The Guntank has returned.
A caterpillar tread was smashed...
So Mr. Kai's Guncannon is out there alone.
He's in danger!
Okay. Just stay calm and tell me
exactly what's happening in battle. Got it?
Sure!
She'll be okay, 'cause I'm with her!
I have you now!
All right!
Damn, I'm out of shells.
Where's that white mobile suit?
The one that killed Mash!
They're the mobile suits
from last night, Amuro.
It'll be tough to defeat them
without the Gundam.
Wanna convert?
White Base, can you hang on for 20 secs?
Mr. Bright! Amuro's asking for 20 seconds!
We've got no choice. Tell Kai to return.
This is for Mash!
Retreat behind the mountain!
R-Roger!
Where does that bomber think it's going?
Separating G-Armor parts.
Pattern G!
Pattern G, acknowledged. Go ahead!
4... 3... 2...
...1... 0.
The one that got Mash appeared
when that bomber came out. That means...
That mobile suit...
Ms. Sayla!
I'll get you!
I'm coming in for a landing, White Base.
All clear?
Okay. Any damage?
A bit along the front.
Roger.
We'll replace it with Hayato's Core Fighter.
Please land on the port-side deck.
Aligning laser axis.
Once it's in the hangar, we'll remove
the front and attach Hayato's Core Fighter.
Roger! Docking release, set.
Please hurry.
Hayato! You'd better not crash it!
Does anybody ever take off
hoping to crash their fighter?
Launching!
The first line to be broken was where
M'Quve's forces were spread thin...
...counting on General Elran's betrayal.
Meanwhile, the two Dom mobile suits...
...were caught up with their battle against
Gundam, and unable to join the front line.
As a result, the Zeon forces lacked
enough strength to stop the Federation.
However, even at this critical moment,
M'Quve still had a last resort.
This is addressed to General Revil,
commander of Operation Odessa!
I am M'Quve.
If you do not withdraw your forces...
...we are prepared to use hydrogen bombs.
Yes, this goes against the Antarctic Treaty
prohibiting the use of nuclear weapons.
But we don't want to lose, either.
It is said that General Revil
did not say a word.
He simply waved his hand
to indicate that his forces were to proceed.
Using those same tactics again?
Don't take us for fools!
O-Ortega... He's...
I-I'll get you...!
Amuro! Do you read me?
The enemy is using a hydrogen bomb!
A hydrogen bomb?! But that's...!
Yes, it is. The enemy is using
a weapon that must never be used.
We have 30 seconds
before the missile launch.
Forget about the mobile suit.
Our priority is to destroy the missile!
But...! There's no way I can do that!
I'm sending you some data.
The red area is the trigger mechanism.
You just need to cut
across the dotted line.
But can such a crude diagram...
really be of any use?
I'm not sure.
It was released when the Antarctic Treaty
was signed, so at least it's reliable.
Incoming!
If it's a real hydrogen bomb,
we'll all be destroyed!
We have to do it, Amuro!
If it's real?
That's right!
If it's real...
Okay. Hayato! Go!
Even Doms can perform stunts like yours!
What?! You mean Revil's forces
haven't stopped their advance?
Yes. They're very close to breaking through
our final line of defense, sir.
Those fools...
It's an enemy mobile suit
battling with a Dom.
So the Federation Forces have taken
drastic measures against us.
Then I'll give them what they asked for.
But sir, it's too late to...
This is how the game is played.
The Federation has blatantly
ignored our demands_
So they must now
face the consequences...
Launch the missile!
Hayato! Full power!
R-Roger that!
Can... I do it?!
M-Mash...
Ortega...
I-I'm sorry...
Operation Odessa has ended in victory
for the Federation Forces.
However, M'Quve has escaped...
...on the Zanzibar warship that had
brought the Black Tri-Stars to Earth.
This battle isn't the end of the war...
Think about it.
With the amount of mineral
resources we've sent...
...Zeon can fight for another 10 years.
The young crew of the White Base...
...are introduced to General Revil
on friendly terms.
The Mad Angler squadron deploys
the amphibious mobile suit Gogg.
In order to crush the Trojan Horse
and destroy the Gundam...
The Goggs attack with extraordinary tactics
as they threaten the White Base.
Yes, the commander of the Mad Angler
squadron is none other than...
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Char Returns.
Next Time
Char Returns
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...